hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says how long is AB and it's giving us
that all semicircles have the same
radius and it's kind of hard to see but
these are red arrows pointed to the
spaces between the semicircles if you
want to try it on your own pause it
right now CU I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 so first let's identify a radius and
since we're given that they all have the
same radius all of these are going to be
the same and then let's look at the top
and the bottom the top is 6 RS plus a 3
plus a 3 and the bottom has four RS plus
a 66 + a 12 + a 66 and we can simplify
both of these 3 + 3 is equal to 6 and 66
+ 12 + 66 is equal to 144 and ultimately
we're trying to find ab ab is going to
be equal to either this top equation or
the bottom equation let's just use the
6r + 6 and then once we solve for R
we'll be able to find ab and the way
we're going to solve for R is this top
has to equal the bottom so that means
that 6r + 6 has to equal 4 r + 144 and
now we have a nice nice equation let's
solve for R we can subtract 4 R from
both sides and subtract six from both
sides on the left hand side the sixes
will cancel each other out and that
leave us with 2 R on the right hand side
the RS will cancel each other out and
that leaves us with 144 - 6 which is 138
next we can divide both sides by two on
the left hand side we have R and on the
right hand side 138 ided 2 is 69 nice
that means that each of these radii are
equal to 69 and now we're ready to solve
for ab in the place of R we can plug in
69 6 * 69 is equal to 414 and 414 + 6 is
420 that is the answer to our question
let's put a box around it the length of
ab in this diagram is equal to 420 how
exciting